Darrin Farr. Chief of police.
Welcome. You Agent Lisbon?
- Yeah. This is Patrick Jane.
- Hey!
Thanks for coming.
I've never called in CBI before.
Interested to see your work.
Okay, victim's name is Lucy Greene.
She was killed last night around 11:00.
- Throat was slit.
- Charming.
She had an army I.D. on her.
Says she's active duty.
Corporal. Probably stationed
at Fort Runyon.
That's about 2 miles
from here, right?
Yeah. Soldiers from the base
come into town all the time.
If the coroner's not here
how did you know the time of death?
The 9-1-1 call came in at 11:00.
Fella said that a woman
had just been killed
across the street from the church.
- The caller give his name?
- No.
Operator asked him to wait
while she dispatched the car.
When she got back on the line,
he was gone.
- What's that?
- The army.
I figured that.
- Chief Farr?
- Yeah?
Lieutenant Averill Lewis
Bravo company, second platoon.
Thanks for notifying us.
Oh, damn.
All right, chief,
we'll take the case from here.
These men are from our criminal
investigation division.
If your officers will let them
have the crime scene?
Lieutenant?
I'm Agent Lisbon with the CBI.
We're handling this.
Ma'am, all due respect, Corporal Greene
was a medic in my platoon.
This is our responsibility.
I understand why you would feel that way
but this is our case.
Chief Farr, REGS
make this your call, right?
Well, I kind of expected your agency
to send more than two people.
- Our staff is on its way.
- Our team is here, Chief.
They've closed homicides
on four continents.
That's a good slogan. Four continents.
What, these guys?
They look like they never
left Salt Lake City.
- Who are you?
- Me? I'm with her.
Lisbon, you used to play clarinet, right?
What is that tune?
Yeah.
It's "Kansas City."
"Kansas City."
- How does that go?
- You know...
"Goin' to Kansas City"
- "Kansas City, here I come"
- "Oh. here I come"
- "They got some crazy little women there"
- "And I'm gonna..."
- "And I'm gonna get me..."
She's very good.
That's very good.
"Kansas City."
It's a classic blues tune.
She's a fan of the blues.
Is there a blues club around here?
Cat's Blues bar.
It's a couple blocks away.
- Well, that's where she was.
- Or not.
Take a look at her left hand.
I'm looking.
If you looked a little closer
than you're looking
you would see
a slight discoloration.
It's not easy to see
but if you put that hand
under a U.V. light
you would clearly see a small
but stylized picture of a pink cat
stamped on that hand.
Just like the ones they use
at the door of bars and clubs.
Hence Cat's Blues bar.
Thank you.
Lieutenant, I think we can handle this.
Looks that way to me.
If that's your decision.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
They got some crazy
little women there...
- All right. Stop that now.
- Army of two.
What do we know
about Lucy Greene?
She was born and raised in New Jersey.
Her parents still live there.
Talked to them.
They were pretty shook up.
Said she seemed pretty happy
the last time they spoke.
She joined the army after 9/11.
Came back from Afghanistan
with her unit about two months ago
- and received an army commendation.
- What for?
She stabilized two wounded soldiers
and hid them from insurgents
until they could be evac'd.
She was a good soldier.
Sounds like it.
What about the mystery 9-1-1 caller?
Well, the phone records confirm
that the call came from a pay phone
near where the body was found.
Supposed to get a recording
of the call later on today.
- E-mail it to me.
- Okay.
Did the victim have any close friends?
Yeah. Her, uh, emergency contact
is another medic in the platoon.
Rose Sutfin.
Jane and I will go talk to her.
Go to town, check out the bar
she was drinking at.
- Who's our liaison at Fort Runyon?
- Lieutenant Lewis.
Great.
Corporal Greene
worked at the hospital.
Most of the medics work there
in some capacity.
Look, I want you to know
there are no hard feelings
about the disposition
of the case
but I'd appreciate being informed
of any developments.
We'll do our best.
How well did you know Lucy?
Not well. I only assumed command
of the platoon a few months ago.
Corporal Sutfin
is doing inventory in here.
Thank you.
This your first significant command?
Yes. It shows, does it?
Ah, just a little.
Corporal Sutfin.
- Sir.
- Ma'am.
At ease, Corporal.
These are the investigators
I spoke with you about.
You'll assist them
with anything they ask.
Yes, sir.
- Which is Lucy's locker?
- Number 116.
Yeah?
There. I had maintenance
open it for you.
Ah, thank you.
How long had you known Lucy?
A couple of years.
Since my first tour in Afghanistan.
- What was she like?
- Smart. Real disciplined.
Lucy didn't have to learn
from mistakes.
She didn't make them.
Well, discipline
always comes with a price.
What did she
have trouble with?
People, I guess.
Guys in the unit, mostly.
She'd be the first to tell you
she was O.C.D. about the rules.
Real detail-oriented.
She'd point out if you messed up
and that doesn't go down well.
Especially with guys.
- You defended her?
- I tried to.
She looked out for me.
Anything unusual
happen recently?
Um... someone
was sending her flowers.
Someone at the clinic.
She wouldn't say who it was
and I think she was a little weirded out.
What clinic?
The T.B.I. and psychological
health clinic.
When she wasn't here,
she worked there.
You should talk to Dr. Bowman.
Her was her supervisor.
Excuse me.
Is that it?
Oh, pretty much.
Uh, you know, unless you wanna
talk about that other thing.
What's that?
The thing that you didn't want me
to ask you about.
I don't know what that is.
Well, neither do I.
Nice to meet you, Rose.
Rigsby just sent over a copy
of the 9-1-1 call. Listen to this.
"Medic... I need a medic, ASAP.
Lucy's hurt."
"Calm down, sir.
Where are you?"
"I'm... uh, I'm on
Wyoga Lake Avenue."
"20 meters north of the church
the St. Sebastian."
"Somebody just cut her throat.
There's blood all over."
"Okay sir, I need you to hold a moment
while I dispatch a car."
- "Will you do that?"
- "Yeah. I'll wait."
"Thank you, sir."
"Hello, sir? Now can you
tell me your name?"
"Hello? Sir? Are you there?"
"He knows her well enough
to call her Lucy"
"and he's very worried
about her."
"But then it seems like he just walks away.
It's weird, isn't it?"
"ASAP". "20 meters".
he's a soldier.
- "We don't open till 6:30."
- "CBI."
Well, then we're open.
Was this woman
here last night?
Yeah. Louise.
No... Lucy.
- What'd she do?
- She was murdered.
- Get out. Seriously? Murdered?
- Yes.
Yeah. She's here
two, three times a week.
- She loves the music.
- Did she come with anyone?
No. Comes by herself.
She did get in an argument
with these soldiers.
They were hassling her.
Couldn't tell you what it was about.
Now, these other soldiers...
you know their names?
Nope. They were in
the Night Wolves unit.
Had the patch on their clothes.
That's her unit.
Her own people were hassling her?
Yeah. Well, it wouldn't surprise me.
The Night Wolves guys are trouble.
- Take after their sergeant.
- You know his name?
- Yeah.
- Hawkins. Sergeant Hawkins.
Sergeant Hawkins?
Yes, sir, I am.
Kimball Cho. CBI.
A word in private?
- Is this about Greene?
- Yes. What can you tell me about her?
Outstanding soldier.
Vital part of the platoon.
It's a... tragedy.
How'd she get along
with the rest of the squad?
- No problems.
- Did she have any enemies?
Enemies? No.
I mean, people fight.
In my unit, we work it out
and put it behind us.
I don't let bad feelings fester.
It takes a unit apart.
Do you know why Lucy was arguing
with some squad mates last night?
That's the first I've heard.
A witness says some of your men
were arguing with Corporal Greene
at a bar last night.
Maybe they are mistaken.
I don't think so.
I'm gonna have to talk to your men.
You be my guest, Agent Cho.
You be my guest.
- Dr. Bowman?
- Yes?
Teresa Lisbon. Patrick Jane.
We're looking into the death
of Lucy Greene.
Oh, of course.
Have a seat, please.
It's terrible.
On top of everything else
Lucy's death's been
a real blow to the program.
She was a tremendous asset.
What's the program?
We treat returning soldiers for T.B.I.
traumatic brain injury.
And other mental health issues
that result from combat.
- Must be busy.
- Unfortunately, yes.
There are a lot of people returning home
with serious problems.
And even minor T.B.I.
can produce sleep deprivation
emotional issues,
memory impairment.
- What did Lucy do?
- She was a battle buddy
a medic, uh, paired with one patient
for the course of treatment.
She was great at it.
Very detail-oriented
but also a huge heart.
So you must have fought with her.
Did you?
Why do you say that?
Well, you're a man who's
used to being obeyed
and she wasn't afraid
to speak her mind.
There must have been
some fireworks.
No. We disagreed sometimes.
That happens.
Well, I imagine you've been
under a great deal of stress
since the divorce?
How do you know I'm divorced?
Well, there's
a... number of signs.
I mean, the obvious is,
the overuse of cologne.
You could probably afford to be
a little less liberal with that.
Making my eyes water.
Well... thanks for the tip.
It's been a little over a year.
I'm doing quite fine, actually,
thanks for asking.
- Good.
- Great.
"Code Red in building 21A."
"Emergency personnel, please respond."
- Uh, what's a Code Red?
- A fire.
It... it's in another building.
The medics on duty in the hospital
act as the base's E.M.T.s
so they make
an announcement in here.
Is... is there anything else?
Because I have patients to see.
Doc? A little help?
Speech and memory class.
Down the hall left,
and left again.
Want someone
to go with you?
I got it. Thanks.
Memory impairment?
Short-term memory's
a real problem.
Things they've seen or heard
just drop out.
- If you'll excuse me.
- Sure.
- Well, come on.
- Why? Where?
Our 9-1-1 caller may not
have run away from the phone.
He may have forgotten about it.
Let's go.
So we're gonna do
an association exercise
using the cards
that you found on your chairs.
It's all about
making connection.
Re-educating the brain
to put things together.
If I were to show you a picture
like this one
I want you to show me
the picture from your cards...
- That matches or... Yes?
- Sorry for the interruption.
I'm Patrick Jane, this is Teresa Lisbon.
We're with the CBI.
We're investigating the murder
of Lucy Greene.
And how can we help you?
We have a recording
made the night of the murder.
Does anyone recognize this voice?
"I'm... I'm on Wyoga Lake Avenue..."
"20 meters north of the church...
the St. Sebastian."
"Somebody just cut her throat.
There's blood all over."
"Okay sir, I need you to hold a moment
while I dispatch a car."
- "Will you do that?"
- "Yeah."
That's my voice. That's me.
- What's your name?
- Pete Coen.
I don't remember any of that.
Pete, we need to talk to you.
Could you come with me, please?
- Yeah, guess.
- Yeah, that's fine, Pete.
Okay.
Thank you.
All of you.
Very much.
- "I'll wait."
- "Thank you, sir."
"Hello, sir?
Now can you tell me your name?"
"Hello? Sir? Are you there?"
"You forgot why you were there
and you just walked away."
Sounds like something I'd do.
We found a date-stamped receipt
from a taco truck in your wallet.
It parks down the street
from the crime scene.
It's dated from the night of the killing.
What were you doing in town?
Walking. When... when I can't sleep,
I go on walks.
The church is 2 miles from the base.
I've got nothing else to do, ma'am.
I like that church. I like the bells.
Can you remember anything
that happened that night?
No.
I'm sorry.
Well, what can
you remember, generally?
Before the explosion's pretty good.
After that...
And when was the... the explosion?
11 months ago in AFFA.
My squad was patrolling Khost.
I got out of a Humvee
to eyeball an intersection.
I waved them through.
And they went right over an I.E.D.
I woke up three days later
in a hospital in Germany.
The other guys...
They...
Now...
My memory is... gone.
I can't sleep.
I... get angry and sad
and I have no idea why.
- Is that to remind you?
- Yeah.
"Take meds"
which, of course,
I didn't remember.
Government gave it to me.
I'm supposed to...
supposed to carry it with me
everywhere that I go.
I have to write down everything
that I'm supposed to do.
that I remember
even if it's in the middle of the night.
Like that helps.
It's useless.
Do you have a... reminder in here
to buy Lucy some flowers?
How'd you know I did that?
Oh, your voice on the 9-1-1 call
sounded like you're a little more
than just friends.
I spent a lot of time with Lucy
in the hospital.
She was always really nice.
You start to think...
maybe there could be
something more, you know?
And...
She was nice about the whole thing but
I think more embarrassed than anything.
Did Lucy make you angry?
- Uh, I mean...
- Mr....
Sorry.
Did she? Make you angry?
- Did who make me angry?
- Lucy?
Lucy Greene?
Why... why are we talking
about Lucy Greene?
Did she... is she okay?
Lucy's dead.
She was murdered.
What?
Do you think there's a chance
he'll remember anything from that night?
Maybe. I-I don't know.
- What time did the 9-1-1 call come in?
- Little bit after 11:00.
Taco.
- I need to go back to the crime scene.
- Why?
Well, I want a taco.
Excuse me.
Where does the taco truck park?
Uh, down that way.
Won't be here
for a few hours, though.
Well, I guess I'll have to wait.
Gardenias.
My favorite.
Could Pete have killed her
and forgot he did it?
It's not impossible.
Go to the hospital and see if anybody
saw him come back that night.
What condition he was in,
if he said anything.
And search his room.
He agreed to it.
- Sure.
- Rigsby...
He may forget who you are
or why you're there.
- Just explain what's going on gently.
- I got it.
Where are we with Lucy's unit?
Everyone in the platoon
agrees with Hawkins.
Lucy was great.
Nobody had a problem with her.
You think the waitress misunderstood
what was going on that night
- or are they lying?
- No. They're lying.
The hospital sent over a list
of patients Lucy worked with.
The most recent one
was a guy named Jacob Lettner.
- See what he has to say.
- Sure.
What exactly did Lucy do for you, Jacob?
She helped me, keep track of medications
and appointments
kept copies of my paperwork.
When things got difficult
she talked me down off the ledge.
Like that.
Sounds like you were close.
Yeah. We, uh... we weren't
dating or anything
but... I liked her.
When's the last time
you saw her?
Well, I was almost done
with the program
so I was only seeing her once a week.
Six days ago, I guess.
- How'd she seem?
- Fine.
Did she mention any problems
with the people in her unit?
Come here.
She, uh... she asked me not
to tell anyone about this.
Like, begged me.
If Lucy had a problem with somebody,
we need to know.
Couple of weeks ago,
she was really upset...
crying, which she never did.
She told me she had filed
a sexual harassment
report anonymously
against someone
in the platoon.
Somehow, some of the guys
found out
and they were giving her
crap about it.
What kind of crap?
Just... you know,
stupid stuff... mean.
- Who did she file the claim against?
- She wouldn't say.
Well, who in the unit
was giving her trouble?
I... I don't know names.
A lot of them.
Sergeant Hawkins,
you lied.
Not true.
You said Lucy
had no problems with the squad
but you knew
she was being punished
because she filed
a sexual harassment complaint.
I knew no such thing.
I had no idea
who filed that complaint.
Now, I was told by
the Inspector General's office
that an anonymous complaint
had been filed
against a soldier
in the platoon.
I investigated
that accusation thoroughly.
How'd you do that?
I questioned every man
and woman in the unit.
Not one said they had seen
or experienced any misconduct.
No witnesses,
no intended victim
no investigation,
so I closed it.
You knew some men
were harassing Lucy
for making the accusation.
If they were, I never heard a word about it
and she never said a thing.
She didn't have to. It's your unit.
It's your job to know what's going on.
But you thought Lucy had become
a troublemaker, didn't you?
You were hoping the backlash
would convince her to transfer.
Is there a question there?
Who was the original harassment
complaint against?
I won't tell you that.
You don't get to choose
which questions you answer.
No? Well, you do
whatever you like.
'Cause I'm not draggin' a good
officer's name through the mud
so that you can go fishing.
Any chance holding Hawkins
will change his mind?
- No.
- Kick him loose, then.
- Something seems off here.
- What?
Everybody says that Lucy
was a stickler for the rules
that she had no problem
speaking up for herself.
But she gets harassed, and she
makes an anonymous complaint?
And when the unit gives her
a hard time about it
she doesn't say anything?
That doesn't sound like her.
Well, she told Lettner
she filed the complaint.
Why would she lie?
Maybe she wanted people
to think she filed it
because she was
protecting someone else.
With your permission, ma'am...
What's this about?
Rose, some people in the unit
think that Lucy filed
an anonymous
sexual harassment complaint.
I think she was taking the heat
for somebody else.
Am I right?
Does this have something to do
with why Lucy was killed?
It might.
I don't know yet.
Was she covering for you, Rose?
Yes.
There's a hotline
I called about four weeks ago.
Please, don't tell my unit.
Please.
You had to have known
an anonymous accusation
was not gonna do much.
I-I guess I hoped that when
the investigation started
other people would come forward
so it wouldn't be just me.
But that didn't happen.
And when Hawkins
started the investigation
people assumed it was Lucy?
Because she was so hardcore
about the rules.
She said it was okay,
that she could take it.
But...
I saw how much it hurt her.
I just wanted
the whole thing to go away.
So... when Hawkins
questioned me
I... I said I didn't
know anything about it.
Rose...
Who did you name
in the complaint?
Who harassed you?
I-I can't talk about it.
It's against REGS.
Hawkins told Cho that he didn't want
to drag an officer's name
through the mud.
An officer, not a soldier.
It was Lewis, wasn't it?
Lewis harassed you.
I didn't...I didn't say that.
I'm not saying that.
- Rose...
- Ma'am, I'd like to leave now.
May I?
- I can't stop you.
- Thanks.
What's up, Rigsby?
I searched Pete's room.
Didn't find anything.
His clothes had been taken for washing
so I tracked 'em down in the laundry.
And?
Found a jacket.
There's bloodstains on it.
Pete is my patient,
and, uh, very fragile.
Do you really need to talk with him
again tonight?
I do.
Well, please keep the questions
short and simple.
Last thing Pete needs
is more stress.
Pete?
Put on your shoes.
We're gonna go out.
Oh, sure.
I'd like that.
What is it, Jane?
Uh, Lisbon... could you bring Pete Coen
to St. Sebastian church in, uh...
- A little under an hour?
- We found blood on his clothes.
I have to take him
to the office for a talk.
Won't do you any good.
You have a better idea?
I'll see you in a little under an hour.
Be prompt.
Jane, what's up?
We're gonna try to restore Pete's memory.
Well, a piece of it, at least.
How could you do that?
Ah, well, I'll explain. But first...
Oh, gracias, señor.
- Taco?
- Sure, thanks.
- Lisbon, you hungry?
- No, thank you.
Okay.
Uh, a memory can be brought back
by a word or an image
but the best tools for digging one out
are the senses...
smell, hearing, taste.
So I'm eating a taco because
I ate one the night Lucy died?
That's right. Taste is first.
Second, coming from the taco truck
you would have walked right by these
beautifully fragrant gardenias.
Okay. I smell it,
but it's not doing anything.
Then, right before the murder
you heard a very distinctive sound.
And you will hear it...
- What sound?
- Wait for it.
- This is really...
- Shh...
Pete?
I remember.
Don't force the memory.
Just... just let it come.
I was here.
"Just walking.
I heard a sound."
Hey!
I couldn't see anything.
By the time my eyes adjusted,
the guy was gone.
And Lucy...
It's difficult, I know.
It's very important to continue.
"I tried to talk to her."
Stay here. Stay here.
Stay with me.
But her throat...
"She just kept
squeezing my hand."
Do you remember anything
about her killer?
His race? His height?
His clothing? Anything?
- I can't talk right now.
- Pete, I need your attention.
I need to write this down.
So I don't forget.
It doesn't eliminate him as a suspect.
He could be lying.
Fine. He's not a suspect.
What else do we have?
Well, Rigsby's got
Lucy's phone records.
He's going through them.
I think we should go after Lewis.
- We don't have anything on him.
- Well, he harassed Rose.
Maybe Lucy threatened him.
Told him that she would have
the investigation reopened.
Maybe.
I agree with Cho.
Man is begging
for some thumbscrews.
You're seriously asking me where I was
when Corporal Greene was killed?
- Answer the question.
- Why?
You were accused
of sexual harassment.
Lucy Greene knew the victim.
That made her dangerous to you.
No, it didn't.
Are you refusing
to answer the question?
The army, in its infinite wisdom
permits the anonymous reporting
of sexual harassment.
Which means any nut
or idiot with an attitude
can make trouble
free of charge.
Some malcontent
made a wild accusation.
It was investigated, nothing was found
there was no victim.
I didn't do anything.
You still haven't told me where you were
when Lucy Greene was killed.
And we checked with
the front gate at the base.
They said you left
in a hurry that day.
I was late.
Getting to a surprise party
for the base commander's wife.
I was there until after midnight.
About 30 people saw me there.
Do you have
any other questions?
Base commander's X.O. confirms
Lewis was at his house until midnight.
Couldn't have done it.
We're a little light on suspects.
I may have something.
Telephone records say
Jacob Lettner
made a bunch of phone calls to
Lucy the day she was murdered.
Well, Lettner told me he hadn't
spoken to Lucy in almost a week.
- We better bring him in.
- I'll go. Someone I need to see.
Okay.
Hey.
More questions, huh?
Well, you got stamina.
I'll give you that.
No questions.
Your men were wrong
about Lucy.
She didn't file
the sexual harassment charge.
She was protecting
the person who did.
Well, that's too bad.
- But it doesn't change anything.
- It should.
Reopen the investigation.
If you don't, you're letting
Lewis off the hook.
Reopen the investigation?
Yeah, yeah, I'll do that.
Why not?
There's no evidence.
He's a lieutenant.
Do you know how fast
he could have a foot up my ass?
All right.
I'm done here.
Talk to Rose.
- Sutfin?
- Just talk to her.
I already did. She said she
didn't know boo about Lewis.
She was scared.
Tell her you'll protect her.
It's not my job
to hold anybody's hand.
You don't have to.
Just don't abandon her
like you abandoned Lucy.
I didn't abandon anybody.
You keep
telling yourself that.
But the next time you ask
someone in this unit
to watch your back, he might
remember how you watched hers.
Jacob, tell us again about
the last time you saw Lucy.
Like I... like I said, it was...
it was more than a week ago.
We know that you spoke to her
on the phone
several times a day
before she died.
You're right.
You're right. I'm sorry.
I forgot.
No, you didn't.
If you want to avoid
getting into trouble
stop lying and tell us
the truth now.
It was nothing.
It was about my meds.
Well, what about them?
I'm about to finish
the program.
Move out on my own.
But Lucy had to certify
that I was capable, you know
that I could take care
of myself.
Keeping on top
of your meds.
Yeah.
But that morning
Lucy told me I'd messed up one of them
taken too little, and I hadn't.
So I told her she made a mistake
which in Lucy's mind is...
It's, like, impossible.
Little miss detail.
So we went a few rounds
on the phone
but she finally agreed to double-check
the prescription records.
Why didn't you tell us
about this earlier?
Because if they think
I messed up my meds
they won't let me live
on my own.
It's wrong.
Look, I'm...
I'm ready.
I am.
Rigsby just talked to Jacob's
boss at the P.X.
He was doing inventory
the night of the murder.
This case is nothing
but dead ends.
Yeah, not necessarily.
Do you have a padlock?
- A padlock?
- Yeah. A lock with a key.
I know what a padlock is, and, no
I do not have a padlock.
Thank you. I'll ask the janitor.
Come in.
Hey.
Mr. Jane.
Is something wrong?
Oh, no, I just had something to do
downstairs.
I thought I'd stop by.
They're nice drawings.
Oh, thanks.
Wow. I know you have trouble
sleeping. I, uh...
I know a technique
that may be helpful.
What kind of technique?
Ah, it's just, mild hypnosis.
Just helps you relax.
What do I have to do?
Lie down and listen.
Sure.
I could really
use some sleep.
- All right, well, just lie down.
- Okay.
Close your eyes.
Breathe.
Fill your mind with all those thoughts
that keep you awake.
Let them crowd around
behind your eyes.
Good.
Now I want you
to paint them black.
Each one of them.
Dark and heavy.
All the same color.
Each one is getting softer...
and heavier.
And quiet...
and peaceful.
- You reach everyone?
- Yep.
Good.
Rigsby, we're a go
in five minutes.
T-minus 5 minutes.
Yep.
What's this about?
Well, we learned of some
evidence this morning
- we need your help with.
- Our help?
What evidence?
Why don't we have Pete tell us?
He's the one who found it.
Hey, what's up, Pete?
I remembered something last night.
I found it on my P.D.A.
this morning.
I must have woken up in the middle
of the night and written it down.
What did you remember?
When Lucy took my hand,
she gave me a key.
A key?
I guess that's why she was
grabbing my hands
so I searched my room,
and I found...
This.
- Can I see that?
- Yes, ma'am.
Does this mean anything to anybody?
- No.
- Not me.
It looks like a medic's locker key
but 107's not Lucy's locker.
Why would she have
another locker?
Hide something.
Well, maybe Lucy found
something incriminating
decided to store it in the locker
and then she was killed for it.
That's why she gave
the key to Pete.
- Lewis, can we search the locker?
- Sure. With a warrant.
- Oh, come on.
- It's my duty to go by the book.
You need a warrant.
It'll take me 20 minutes
to get one.
Ah, Lewis.
Such a stickler.
It's just gonna be a little while longer.
"Code Red in building 17D."
"All emergency personnel
respond immediately."
That's me. Uh, sorry.
Okay, well, thank you all for your help.
We'll let you know what we find.
"Code Red in building 17D."
"All emergency personnel
respond immediately."
Hey, Doc. What are you doin'?
I...
"Eh, uh, uh..."
You're a silver-tongued devil.
We found a significant number
of cash deposits in your account.
You were writing
fake prescriptions
and selling the drugs
under the table for cash.
That's what Lucy found
when she looked into
Jacob's prescription records.
- Are you divorced, Agent?
- No.
You have no idea
how expensive it is.
I'm paying legal fees,
alimony, child support...
And all so the lying bitch
can be supported
in the manner to which
she's accustomed.
What about the manner
to which I'm accustomed?
What about my lifestyle?
- And dating isn't cheap.
- Really?
Lucy came to me.
The diligent fool.
Said she found some serious problems
with the prescriptions.
No idea I was behind it, but...
She's all gung ho to launch
a big investigation.
That's how she was.
"She said she was going
to the blues club that night, so..."
"I waited down the street."
Lucy?
- Doctor?
- Yeah.
What are you doing here?
There's a man hurt back here.
Come and help me.
Uh, okay. Sure.
Only took a second.
Takes about a minute to bleed to death
so I waited.
Hey!
This is not my fault.
If my ex-wife had just agreed
to a reasonable settlement
none of this would have happened.
Oh, well...
look on the bright side.
In prison, you won't
have to pay for dates.
What are you doing here?
- Just watching.
- Excuse me?
Lieutenant Lewis.
I need to speak with you.
Later, Sergeant Hawkins.
I'm busy.
No, sir. We need to do this ASAP.
It's regarding a code violation.
Are you serious?
Sir, we have to go now.
Hawkins.
I got your message, Mr. Jane.
- I'm sorry.
- No, it's...
No. It's good. Good.
Pete, thank you for coming by.
I just... I wanted to apologize
for tricking you without asking.
The gag wouldn't have
worked without it.
Sorry.
You got the guy who killed Lucy.
That's good enough for me.
I'm... actually here
about that other thing.
Do you really think you could
help restore my memory?
Well, I do have a tool
that could be very useful.
- Have a seat.
- All right.
It's called a memory palace.
It's basically a place
to connect memories to.
You said I would need the image
of a place I knew really well.
- Yes, that's right.
- I think I got one.
These are my buddies from Khost.
This picture was taken in our tent
about two weeks before.
I spent...
I spent 14 months
in that tent with those guys.
I know every inch of it.
Good.
Who was the first person you saw
when you woke up in the morning?
Ford.
Danny Ford.
Lazy bastard's always sleeping in.
He could sleep right through a firefight.
Okay. Here's how it works.
Well, let's say you need to remember
a dentist's appointment,
Monday, 10:00 a.m.
I want you to imagine seeing Danny
holding something ridiculous
that makes you think of a dentist.
- Like what, a giant tooth?
- Exactly.
Now who was in the bunk
right next to Danny?
Because they're gonna help you
recall the day.
- Vasquez is.
- Okay. Can you imagine...